So we need to figure out something different. There's no
我们需要从不同的角度思考问题
sensible base case that gives us a good recursive definition.
我们没有一个合理的基本情况 来得出好的递归定义
What we're do, going to do instead is what's called a
我们将转而使用松弛算法
relaxation algorithm. And the basic idea is pretty simple. We're
理论很简单
going to start with a guess and then we're going to have
我们将从一个猜测开始
some loop where we keep going. We'll just say, while
然后进行某种循环 直接写为
we're not done, we'll figure out how to decide when
如果我们还未完成 我们将弄清楚如何判断是否已完成
we're done. We're going to do something that makes a guess better.
我们将采取某种操作使猜测更准确
So, that's the basic idea. That we don't have a good
基础理论就是这样 我们没有好的停止点
stopping point and we don't have a clear starting point of saying
我们没有一个清晰的起始点
Alice's popularity is one, and we're going to define everything in that.
不能假设 Alice 的受欢迎程度是 1 然后接着定义
What we're going to do instead is we're going to start with a guess,
我们将先从一个猜测开始
and our guess could be, well, let's assume everyone's initial popularity
我们的猜测是 假设所有人的初始受欢迎程度都是 1
is one. And then we're going to keep refining the guess. We're going to
然后不断完善猜测
have some process that updates the guess based on what we've learned.
我们有一个流程 根据所得出的结论更新猜测
And each time we do this, we're going to get better and better.
每次进行这个流程 我们的猜测就越来越准确
And at some point we're going to stop and we're
最终将会停止
going to say well that's the result we want. So let's
并得出我们想要的结果
think about how to do that for popularity scores.
我们看看如何这么计算受欢迎程度得分
So, instead of just having one input to popularity now,
现在 popularity 有 2 个输入 而不是 1 个
there's going to be two. It's going to take the
它将传入步骤数
time step, that's the number of times we've tried to
即我们已经尝试猜测过的次数
guess. And it's going to take the person, and it's
并传入相关的人名
still going to output a score. And now we can define
输出依然为得分 现在可以定义成
this in a way that we do have a starting
我们的确有一个起始点
point, which is the equivalent to having a stopping point in
就相当于在递归定义中有一个停止点
a recursive definition. We'll define what the value is at
我们将定义第 0 步时的值
step zero. For any person, we'll say that the score is
对任何人来说 我们都假设得分是 1
1. And it didn't work to have a base case,
我们没有成功获取基本情况
in terms of the person, because there's no clear ordering of
当只有 person 参数的时候 因为人们没有清晰的顺序
the people. We had a graph, we had lots of different
我们有一个图 其中有很多不同的友谊连接
friendship connections, there was no clear starting point. We're going to add
没有清晰的起始点 我们将添加
an extra parameter which is our, our time step, and
一个额外的参数 即步骤数
that's going to be our base case. And if we think
这将是我们的基本情况
of our time step as our base case, it's easy
如果将步骤数考虑到基本情况中
to say that time step zero is our base case. And
那么就可以说步骤 0 是我们的基本情况
at step zero, we're going to say everyone's popularity score is
在步骤 0 时 我们说所有人的受欢迎程度得分是 1
one. And now we can have our update rule, which
现在就可以得出更新规则了
says, we can figure out the popularity at any time
我们可以得出在任意步骤 t
step t, where t is greater than 0 for any person,
(其中 t>0) 任何人的受欢迎程度
and we're going to define that as the sum
我们将其定义为所有好友的累加值
over all their friends. So we're going to pick a
我们将从好友集合中
friend in their set of friends. So we're
选择一个好友
going to go through each friend summing up the popularity
我们将计算每个好友的受欢迎程度得分之和
score of the friend. But instead of at time t, we're going to use time t minus
我们将使用步骤 t-1 而不是步骤 t
1. So that means we're looking for the
也就是说我们要计算
popularity of the friend in the previous step and
上一步骤的好友受欢迎程度
we're using that to compute the popularity of
我们将使用该值来计算
the person they're friends with in this step. So
在此步骤中的好友受欢迎程度
let me write out that more in pseudocode. If
我用伪代码来表示
we think of this as the Python procedure, it's
如果将此看做 Python 过程
going to be something where we're taking in two
我们将传入两个输入
imports now, the time and the person. And now
步骤和人名
we have the base case, if the time is
现在有了基本情况
0, we're going to return the score is always 1.
如果步骤是 0 我们将返回始终为 1 的得分
If the time is not 0, well, we can compute the score similar to how we did
如果步骤不是 0 则得分计算方法和之前的相似
before. We're going to have the score at 0, we're
我们将初始化 score 为 0
going to sum over the friends. We're summing over the
我们将对好友求和
friends, updating the score, by adding the friends' popularity
通过加上上一步骤的好友受欢迎程度得分
score at the previous step. And when we're done,
更新 score 循环完成后
the value of score is the result. So now
score 的值就是结果
we have our new definition. We have it written
现在我们拥有了新的定义
in mathematical notation at the top, and in the
上面是数学符号的定义
Python code here. So the question is, is this a
这里是 Python 代码 问题是
good recursive definition? And I don't mean to ask whether
这是好的递归定义吗？我并不是问
it's a good definition of popularity, let's hope it's not.
这是否是好的受欢迎程度定义 希望不是
What I mean to ask is, for all possible inputs,
我想问的是 对于所有可能的输入
so all values we can pass in as t and
对于所有传入的 t 和 p 值
p, does the way we've defined popularity give us a
我们定义受欢迎程度的方式能给出结果吗？
result? So here the possible choices. So, yes, it's only
选项如下 选项 1 Yes
good if people can't be friends with themself. It's good
选项 2 仅当人们无法与自己是好友时才是一个好定义
only if everyone has at least one friend. Hopefully, everyone
选项 3 仅当所有人都至少有 1 个好友时才是一个好定义
does. But it's only a good definition if that's the
希望大家都至少有 1 个好友
case. Or only if everyone is more popular than Alice.
或者 仅当所有人都比 Alice 更受欢迎时才是一个好定义